<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on</title><link>/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Collins: Sounds in Space</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-4/collins-sounds-in-space/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-4/collins-sounds-in-space/</guid><description>The Doppler Effect Why does the doppler shift happen?</description></item><item><title>Film Scoring Examples</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-12/film/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-12/film/</guid><description>Philip Glass Koyaanisqatsi / (1982) Philip Glass is one of the early proponents of minimalism, a genre of music that is based on simple diatonic harmony, repetitive rhythmic structures, and additive processes (slowly adding different layers to the sound).
The Hours (2002) Hans Zimmer Inception (2010) Interstellar (2014) Dunkirk (2017) Dune (2021) Cliff Martinez The Knick (2014) Drive (2011) Mica Levi Under the skin (2014) Jóhann Jóhannsson Sicario (2015) Arrival (2016)</description></item><item><title>Live Demo Mix</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-7/live-demo-mix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-7/live-demo-mix/</guid><description>Find the live demo set.
Tracks Drum Rack See drum rack busses Signal is routed to a kick, snare, or hihat bus, each with a variety of effects on them. See automation on snare bus and hihat bus effects Perc choice cut out the lows on the pandeiro so we only hear the high hat, overdrive to add some crunch Clap loop Multiband compression Hihat Loop sidechain compression the compressor is taking audio as an input from the drum rack the threshold is set so that only the kickdrum triggers the compressor the effect is that the hihat loop is ducked so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t clash with the kick drum Break loop multiband compression helps bring the elements together, it needs this because there are is a wide range of frequencies in the break loop see the automation on delay time, this is just to give the break loop some variation the effect of the delay is to make the loop sound thicker and wider as the delay time is 13.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>/pages/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/projects/</guid><description>Project 1 Make 10 field recordings, either on a Zoom portable recorder or your phone. Try to record at several distances, adjusting the gain but increasing the distance from the microphone to sound source, starting in the intimate zone and then moving farther out. What are the changes you notice in the sound acoustically and perceptually?
Recordings can either focus on specific things such as a bird or a car driving by, or be an ambience, where the focus is on the wider soundscape.</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>/pages/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/resources/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Review of Sound, Listening and Place: The aesthetic dilemma</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-4/truax-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-4/truax-review/</guid><description>Audio examples from reading Sonification &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; Phonology &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; Virtual Soundscapes Sonification Audication of the sun Sonification of median household incomes along a subway line in NYC John Luther Adams - The Place Where You Go to Listen - an example of a sound sculpture, driven by data. Make your own data sonifications Phonology Sound map Wilderness livestreams?</description></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>/pages/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/schedule/</guid><description>table { border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; } tr { border-bottom: 1px solid #ccc; } th { text-align: left; } } Week Date Topics, Assignments, Quizzes, Tests, Deadlines 1 8/24, 8/26 Tuesday 8/24
Me - Dr. Carson Class introductions Name? Class year? Where are you from? What is your interest in sound design? What do you want to learn more of?</description></item><item><title>Syllabus</title><link>/pages/syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/syllabus/</guid><description>Course Syllabus Course Prefix, Number, and Title: DAD 310 - Digital Soundtrack Production
Credits: 3
University Name: Dakota State University
Academic Term/Year: Fall 2021
Last date to Drop and receive 100% refund: September 2nd, 2021 Last date to Withdraw and earn a grade of &amp;lsquo;W&amp;rsquo;: November 5th, 2021 Course Meeting Time and Location: MWF 2:30 pm – 5:00 pm TCB 209
Instructor Information: Instructor Information: Name: Tate Carson Office: TCB 305 Email Address: Tate.</description></item><item><title>Three-Dimensional Sound</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-7/three-dimensional-sound/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-7/three-dimensional-sound/</guid><description>Sounds in space - four dimensions three cartesian dimensions - x (left to right), controlled by panning y (top to bottom), pitch perception, higher frequencies sound high on the y axis z (front to back) Louder sounds appear closer to us. Sounds without reverb (when used in conjunction with sounds with reverb) will sound closer to us (since the reverberation implies a space between us and the sounds).</description></item></channel></rss>